Guide to the College of Human Ecology Social Work Program records, [ca.1975-2000]
New York State College of Human Ecology. Social Work Program records, [ca.1975-2000]
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Social Work Program Records, ca.1975-2000
23-24-3184
New York State College of Human Ecology. Social Work Program.
2.3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, publications, photographs, and program and course material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, publications, photographs, program and course material documenting the undergraduate Social Work Program that was in the Department of Human Service Studies in the New York State College of Human Ecology. Includes correspondence to and from Josephine Allen, professor in the Department of Policy Analysis and Management in the College of Human Ecology.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, publications, photographs, program and course material documenting the undergraduate Social Work Program that was in the Department of Human Service Studies in the New York State College of Human Ecology. Includes correspondence to and from Josephine Allen, professor in the Department of Policy Analysis and Management in the College of Human Ecology.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Human Ecology. Social Work Program.; Allen, Josephine Aona V.; New York State College of Human Ecology. Dept. of Human Service Studies.; New York State College of Human Ecology. Dept. of Policy Analysis and Management.
Subjects:
Social work education.; Social sciences--Study and teaching.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Publications/Manuals
Box 1 and Box 2, Folder 1
Series II. Programs/Workshops
Box 2, Folders 2-8
Series III. Course Material
Box 2, Folders 9-15
Series IV. Accreditation Material
Box 2, Folders 16-23
Series V. Correspondence
Box 2, Folders 24-27
Series VI. Alumni Material, Awards, Handbooks
Box 3, Folders 1-7
Series VII. Fieldwork Placements
Box 3, Folders 8-16
Series VIII. Memorabilia
Box 4
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Publications/Manuals
  - Field Instruction Manual, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - An Introduction to the Cornell University Social Work Program (Box 1)
  - Baccalaureate Self-Study Report, Volume II, 1976-1982 (Box 1)
  - Field Instruction Manual, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Field Instruction Manual, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Field Instruction Manual, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Student Field Manual, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Field Instruction Manual, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Student Field Manual, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Field Instruction Manual, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  - Student Field Manual, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  - Student Field Manual, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - An Introduction to the Cornell University Social Work Program, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - An Introduction to the Cornell University Social Work Program, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  - Advising Handbook, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Advising Handbook, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - Advising Handbook, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - Advising Handbook (Box 1)
  - Advising Handbook (Box 1)
  - Report to the Council on Social Work Education, April 1996 (Box 1)
  - Reaccreditation Self-Study, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Student Field Manual, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - Supervisor?s Field Manual--Evaluative Standards, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - Supervisor's Field Manual, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - Fieldwork Manual, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  - Field Instruction Manual for Social Work Interns, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - Fieldwork Manual, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - Fieldwork Manual, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Fieldwork Manual, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - Fieldwork Manual, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - Fieldwork Manual, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - HSS 246--Determinants of Human Behavior, Fall 1987 (Box 1)
  - Human Ecology Student Guide, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Research and Undergraduate Social Work Education: A Report Into the Profession, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Statistics on Social Work Education In the United States: 1998, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Statistics on Social Work Education In the United States: 1995, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Statistics on Social Work Education In the United States: 1996, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Social Work Laws and Board Regulations, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Social Work Perspectives, 97 Vol. 7 #1, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Social Work Handbook, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Newspapers, 1994-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Social Work--Newsletters, Publicity, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Series II. Programs/Workshops
  - Managed Care Workshop, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Summer Faculty Development Program, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Position Paper-New York State Social Work Education Association-by Diane Strock-Lynskey, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Social Work Program?Undergraduate Self Study, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Social Work?An Introduction to the CU Social Work Program (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Case Studies to be Used for the Cornell Social Work Program Competency Examination (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - BPD-IASWR-NIMH-Summer Intensive Faculty Dev. Program, 1997-1999 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series III. Course Material
  - Course Materials--HSS 370, 1979-1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Course Materials--HSS 475 & 675, 1979-1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Course Materials--HSS 660, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Course Materials--HSS 402, 474, 417, 202, 1977-1983 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Comprehensive Exams #1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Comprehensive Exams #2 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Course material, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Series IV. Accreditation Material
  - Social Work Program--Reaccreditation, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Social Work Program--Reaccreditation, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 16A)
  - Reaccreditation Application, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Reaccreditation Application, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Accreditation, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Department of Human Service Studies Review, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Social Work Program Review, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Reaccreditation-includes site visit report, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Accreditation, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Series V. Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Social Work Program application process and program evaluation, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Photographs (Box 2)
- Series VI. Alumni Material, Handbooks, Awards
  - Survey of Social Work Graduates 19731993; Interim Report fo CSWE; New York State Bill (copy); Report on the Future of Social Work at Cornell, 1973-1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Alumni Survey, 1994 and 1997; Information about Alumni, 1975-1997, 1975-1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - National Association of Social Workers-National Awards Recipients, 1968-1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Social Work Advisory Committee, 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Handbook of Accreditation Standards and Procedures, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Certificates (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Student Social Workers Handbook, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Series VII. Fieldwork Placements in Social Work
  - Fieldwork Placements-Background, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Fieldwork Placements-McCormick Center, 1988-1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Fieldwork Placements-Family & Children?s Service and Tompkins Community Hospital, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Tompkins County Office for the Aging, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Fieldwork Placement-Homes, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Fieldwork Placement-The Learning Web (2 placements, 1987-1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Fieldwork Placement-Hillel, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Fieldwork Placement-Lakeside Nursing Center (1988-1989); Suicide Prevention and Crisis Center (1987-1988), 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Fieldwork Placement-Ithaca Housing Authority and TC3, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Photographs
- Series VIII. Memorabilia
  - Banner "Association of Students Social Workers" - Poster Created by National Association of Social Workers (Box 4)